

**EMAIL**: esmyser@gmail.com

**PHONE:** 646.270.9942

**GITHUB:** <a href="https://github.com/esmyser">https://github.com/esmyser</a>

BLOG: http://esmyser.github.io/

## Ezra Smyser



#### BIO

Crutches made me a coder. Repeatedly sidelined by injuries from the sports I love, I left my product manager job to solve a serious problem for runners: finding the right shoe. Working part-time at a running store, I created an algorithm to match people's needs to shoes. But I couldn't code. No team to build the product, no product to attract a team: end of project. Since graduating from college, my entire career has been a series of experiences that ultimately ended in "If only I could code."

Studying philosophy, I learned to use logic to solve theoretical questions. When I started working in startups I realized how much I enjoy solving real world problems. Now at Flatiron, I've ignited a passion for technical challenges. Coding is the tool of change, and I'm excited to build solutions that can change lives.

#### **APPLICATIONS BUILT**

#### Pretender.io - Rails, Postgres, Redis, Ajax

When meeting someone new, pretender helps you know what to talk about

- + Collected individuals' interests from tweets, favorites, and the people they follow on Twitter
- + Implemented asynchronous Redis jobs for large tasks
- + Used Pusher to update frontend when Redis jobs are completed
- + Created service objects to simplify logic in controllers

#### Github | Site

#### **Down to Earth -** *Node.js*

Spin the globe and visit a streetview anywhere in the world

- + Animated spinning globe with WebGL Earth API
- + Rendered closest street view with GoogleMaps API
- + Simplified code with object orientated javascript

#### Github | Site

#### Attack of the Reviews - Rails, Ajax

Aggregates restaurant reviews from Yelp, foursquare, and Google APIs

- + Normalized addresses to merge data from multiple APIs
- + Generated dynamic query based on marker location in embedded google map

#### Github



# Ezra Smyser

### **EDUCATION**

Washington University in St. Louis, 2011 Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy

JackRabbit, to learn how roadmap with Chief

**Product Officer** 

they recommend shoes

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY			
Helix Running	Jirafe Analytics	Timehop, FieldLens, & Matchbook	Craft Coffee
New York, NY	New York, NY	New York, NY	New York, NY
<b>Founder</b> Apr 2014 - Apr 2015	Product Manager Mar 2012 - Mar 2014	<b>Shared Intern</b> Jan 2012 - Mar 2012	<b>Intern</b> Oct 2011 - Dec 2011
+ Created algorithm to match user needs to shoes	+ Managed product lifecycle across frontend and backend teams	+ Developed competitive analysis reports for FieldLens that were given to investors	+ Implemented new initiative to enhance delivery experience for customers for holiday
+ Hired and managed two contract developers	+ Led major releases including our flagship	+ Supported customers	rush season
to build proof of concept that makes accurate recommendations	analytics product and payment model	and obtained product feedback for Matchbook	<ul> <li>+ Improved assembly line process for packaging by adding</li> </ul>
+ Released non-scalable	+ Distilled business needs into	+ Contacted publications for Timehop marketing;	incremental efficiencies
MVP to gather early user feedback	requirements, specs, and wireframes	facilitated features in two blogs	+ Standardized and managed process for curating coffees and
+ Worked at the best running store in NYC,	+ Planned quarterly goals against product		communicating with roasters